

TYLER FORD

Web Developer ♥ SALT LAKE CITY, 84108, UNITED STATES 4356406878

o DETAILS o

2464 Skyline Dr, Salt Lake City, 84108, United States 4356406878 tylerford@gmail.com

PLACE OF BIRTH Gilroy, CA

NATIONALITY American

o LINKS o

<u>Github</u>

o SKILLS o

Front End Development

Programming

Visual Design Skills

Knowledgable in User Interface/ User Experience

Adaptability

○ HOBBIES ○

Hockey, Hiking, Smoking Meats, Writing

PROFILE

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience in copy-writing, video production, and digital marketing, educated at the University of Utah. Skills in HTML, CSS and JavaScript and strengths in meeting deadlines, creativity and teamwork. Oversaw branded redesign of the company website, and created a branded Capital Campaign website and video that has to date raised over 4 million dollars. Excited to approach programming challenges from different angles and collaborate with others to create useful web applications. Positioned well to provide unique perspectives on how end-users interact with websites, software platforms, and emails by leveraging my background in digital marketing.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Marketing Communications Manager / Front End Designer at I.J. & Jeanné Wagner Jewish Community Center, Salt Lake City

August 2015 - Present

- Oversaw branded redesign of the company website, and created a branded Capital Campaign website and video that has to date raised over 4 million dollars.
- Led transition from print-heavy advertising and publications to measurable digital advertisements, and consistent mobile-friendly e-newsletters and donation forms.
- Developed meaningful content to build engagement including hundreds of original videos, gifs, and photographs.
- Worked well independently and within a team setting.

Public Relations Associate at Tanner Humanities Center, Salt Lake City

October 2014 – July 2015

- Coordinated all aspects of monthly National Theater Live film screenings including program selection & scheduling, promotion, production, ticketing database management, and reporting.
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues.
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.

EDUCATION

University of Utah, Salt Lake City

August 1999 - May 2010

Degree: Bachelor of Cinema Arts

COURSES

Full Stack Developer Boot Camp, University of Utah

June 2019 - December 2019

Web Design Tools, University of Utah April 2012 – July 2012

REFERENCES

References available upon request